Guide to the Carl Van Vechten Papers Relating to African American Arts and Letters
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Photographs, 1932–1964; Series IV; 157.31 linear feet
  - Photographic Postcards, 12 linear feet
    - Events
      - Wedding Reception for Carmen De Lavallade and Geoffrey Holder at the Clarence Derwent House, Westport, Connecticut.
        - Banfield, Clive, with Carmen De Lavallade, Elaine De Lavallade, and Geoffrey Holder, 1955 June 26; 8 photographic postcards (Box 222, Folder 3932)
        - Carroll, Diahann, and Elwyn M. Chamberlain, 1955 June 26; 7 photographic postcards (Box 222, Folder 3933)
        - Carroll, Diahann, with Carmen De Lavallade and Saul Mauriber, 1955 June 26; 8 photographic postcards (Box 222, Folder 3934)
        - De Lavallade, Carmen, 1955 June 26; 3 photographic postcards (Box 222, Folder 3935)
        - De Lavallade, Carmen, with Elaine De Lavallade and Geoffrey Holder, 1955 June 26; 12 photographic postcards (Box 222, Folder 3936)
        - De Lavallade, Carmen, with Geoffrey Holder, and Lucille Lortel, 1955 June 26; 7 photographic postcards (Box 222, Folder 3937)
        - De Lavallade, Carmen, with Geoffrey Holder, Fania Marinoff, and Carl Van Vechten, 1955 June 26; 2 photographic postcards (Box 222, Folder 3938)
          Roll number IX nn. Photography by Saul Mauriber.
        - Johnson, Louis, 1955 June 26; 10 photographic postcards (Box 222, Folder 3939)
        - Premice, Josephine, 1955 June 26; 6 photographic postcards (Box 222, Folder 3940)
        - Wedding cake, 1955 June 26; 5 photographic postcards (Box 222, Folder 3941)
      - Performances
        - Davis, Sammy, Jr., at a National Urban League benefit at Birdland, Manhattan, New York City, 1956 June 10; 20 photographic postcards (Box 222, Folder 3942)
    - Artwork
      - Bell, Mary A. Happiness, 1936-1939, drawing, 1937 May 23; 1 photographic postcard (Box 222, Folder 3943)
        Roll number XXX k.
      - Chamberlain, Elwyn M. Celebration, circa 1954, sketch, 1955 June 17; 5 photographic postcards (Box 222, Folder 3944)
        Trimmed postcards
      - Cleveland, Lady Bird. Eartha Kitt, circa 1954, painting, 1954 October 5; 8 photographic postcards (Box 222, Folder 3945)
      - Cleveland, Lady Bird. Eartha Kitt, circa 1954, painting, 1954 November 16; 8 photographic postcards (Box 222, Folder 3946)
      - Epstein, Jacob. Paul Robeson, 1928, sculpture, 1933 September 5; 1 photographic postcard (Box 222, Folder 3947)
      - Holder, Geoffrey. Voodoo Ceremony (Self-portrait), 1955, painting, 1955 June 17; 8 photographic postcards (Box 222, Folder 3948)
        Trimmed postcard prints.
      - Lucioni, Luigi, Ethel Waters, 1939, painting, 1939 June 6; 11 photographic postcards (Box 222, Folder 3949)
      - Salemme, Antonio. Ethel Waters, 1928, sculpture, 1932 February 22; 4 photographic postcards (Box 222, Folder 3950)
      - Wilson, Ellis, Marchand, circa 1947, painting, 1959 August 12; 13 photographic postcards (Box 222, Folder 3951)
  - Color Slides, 5.16 linear feet
    Color slides of African Americans as well as events and sites related to them. The 2,240 slides are color transparency frames of 35-millimeter film in cardboard mounts that measure 2 inches by 2 inches (5.08 centimeters by 5.08 centimeters) and depict 454 individual portrait settings, events, or sites. The slides are primarily physically arranged by sequential numbers as well as by image set numbers in metal slide files storage boxes manufactured by the Brumberger Sales Corporation circa 1950.
    Existence and Location of Copies
    Digital surrogates for slides in this component are available in the Digital Collections.
    - Portraits
      - Abrahams, Peter, 1955 November 25; 21 color slides (Box 225)
        Slide numbers 1799, 1800, 1801, 1802, 1803, 1804, 1805, 1806, 1807, 1808/1809, 1810, 1811, 1812, 1813, 1814, 1815, 1816, 1817, 1818, 1819, 1820. Image set number XCIc.
      - Abutu, Etuka Okala, Prince, 1946 November 16; 3 color slides (Box 224)
        Slide numbers 922, 923, 924. Image set number CCXLVIIa.
      - Addison, Adele, 1955 April 8; 15 color slides (Box 224)
        Slide numbers 1266, 1267, 1268, 1269, 1270, 1271, 1272, 1273, 1274, 1275, 1276, 1277, 1278, 1279, 1280. Image set number LXXIIc.
      - Ailey, Alvin, 1955 March 22; 19 color slides (Box 224)
        Slide numbers 1637, 1638, 1639, 1640, 1641, 1642, 1643, 1644, 1645, 1646, 1647, 1648, 1649, 1650, 1651, 1652, 1653, 1654, 1655. Image set numbers. LXVIIIc and LXIXc.
      - Allen, Betty, 1958 April 3; 13 color slides (Box 224)
        Slide numbers 1434, 1435, 1436, 1437, 1438, 1439, 1440, 1441, 1442, 1443, 1444, 1445, 1446. Image set number CXXIVc. Image numbers 1441-1444 have tape affixed that crops the visible image.
      - Allen, Sanford, 1964 November 3; 7 color slides (Box 226)
        Slide numbers 2278, 2279, 2280, 2281, 2282, 2283, 2284. No image set number.
      - Anderson, Marian, 1940 January 14; 6 color slides (Box 223)
        Slide numbers 63, 64, 65, 66, 67, 68/69. Image set number LXVII.
      - Anderson, Marian, 1947 July 17; 8 color slides (Box 223)
        Slide numbers 70/71, 72, 73/74, 75, 76, 77, 78, 79/80. Image set number CCLXIIIa.
      - Arroyo, Martina, 1961 April 4; 5 color slides (Box 225)
        Slide numbers 1710, 1711, 1712, 1713, 1714. Image set number CLXVIIIc.
      - Attaway, William, 1941 October 29; 3 color slides (Box 223)
        Slide numbers 662, 663, 664. Image set number CCCLXXVII.
      - Ayler, Ethel, as Zirata in Simply Heavenly, musical with book and lyrics by Langston Hughes and music by David Martin, 1957 June 10; 6 color slides (Box 224)
        Slide numbers 1360, 1361, 1362, 1363, 1364, 1365. Image set number CXVIIc.
      - Ayler, Ethel, as Zirata, and Melvin Stewart as Simple in Simply Heavenly, musical with book and lyrics by Langston Hughes and music by David Martin, 1957 June 10; 3 color slides (Box 224)
        Slide numbers 1357, 1358, 1359. Image set number CXVIIc.
      - Bailey, Pearl, 1946 July 5; 16 color slides (Box 223)
        Slide numbers 605, 606, 607, 608, 609, 610, 611/612, 625, 626/627, 628, 629, 630, 631, 632, 633/636, 637. Image set numbers. CXXXIIa and CXXXIIIa.
      - Bailey, Pearl, 1950 March 12; 5 color slides (Box 223)
        Slide numbers 638, 639, 640, 641, 642. Image set number XLVIIIb.
      - Bailey, Pearl, as Butterfly in St. Louis Woman, musical by Harold Arlen and Johnny Mercer, 1946 July 5; 12 color slides (Box 223)
        Slide numbers 613, 614, 615, 616, 617, 618, 619, 620, 621, 622, 623, 624. Image set number CXXXIIa.
      - Bailey, Pearl, as Connecticut in Arms and the Girl, musical with music by Morton Gould, lyrics by Dorothy Fields, and book by Herbert Fields, Dorothy Fields and Rouben Mamoulian, 1950 March 12; 15 color slides (Box 223)
        Slide numbers 643, 644, 645, 646, 647, 648, 649, 650, 651, 652, 653, 654, 655, 656, 657/661. Image set number XLVIIIb.
      - Baldwin, James, 1955 September 13; 15 color slides (Box 225)
        Slide numbers 1761, 1762, 1763, 1764, 1765, 1766, 1767, 1768, 1769, 1770, 1771, 1772, 1773, 1774, 1775. Image set number LXXXVIIIc.
      - Ballard, David, and Esther Howard at New York World's Fair, Flushing Meadows-Corona Park, New York City, 1940; 2 color slides (Box 223)
        Slide numbers 204, 205. Image set number CCXXXVIII. Ballard was a giant and Howard was a little person
      - Baraka, Amiri, 1962 January 3; 3 color slides (Box 226)
        Slide numbers 2162, 2163, 2164. Image set number CLXXXc. Inscription references his former name, Le Roi Jones.
      - Barthé, Richmond, 1939 September 23; 2 color slides (Box 223)
        Slide numbers 33, 34. Image set numbers. XXXVIII and XXXVIIIb. No. 33 has 1-cent postage stamps affixed to crop the portrait.
      - Barthé, Richmond, 1949; 4 color slides (Box 223)
        Slide numbers 35, 36, 37, 38. Image set number XXIb.
      - Bass, Maudelle, and Lawaune Kennard in Black Ritual (Obeah), ballet choreographed by Agnes de Mille, music by Darius Milhaud, 1940 April 8; 3 color slides (Box 223)
        Slide numbers 457, 458, 460. Image set number LXXXVII.
      - Bass, Maudelle, in Black Ritual (Obeah), ballet choreographed by Agnes de Mille, music by Darius Milhaud, 1940 April 8; 2 color slides (Box 223)
        Slide numbers 464, 465. Image set number LXXXVII.
      - Bass, Maudelle, with Muriel Cook and Dorothy Williams in Black Ritual (Obeah), ballet choreographed by Agnes de Mille, music by Darius Milhaud, 1940 April 8; 2 color slides (Box 223)
        Slide numbers 455, 456. Image set number LXXXVII.
      - Bass, Maudelle, with Muriel Cook and Lawaune Kennard in Black Ritual (Obeah), ballet choreographed by Agnes de Mille, music by Darius Milhaud, 1940 April 8; 1 color slide (Box 223)
        Slide number 459. Image set number LXXXVII.
      - Bass, Maudelle, with Muriel Cook, Lawaune Kennard, and Dorothy Williams in Black Ritual (Obeah), ballet choreographed by Agnes de Mille, music by Darius Milhaud, 1940 April 8; 1 color slide (Box 223)
        Slide number 471. Image set number LXXXVII.
      - Belafonte, Harry, 1954 February 18; 12 color slides (Box 224)
        Slide numbers 1165, 1166, 1167, 1168, 1169, 1171, 1172, 1173, 1174, 1175, 1176. Image set number XLIVc.
      - Beresford, Roy Thompson,at the opening of The Art of the Negro in Dance, Music and Drama exhibition at the Museum of the City of New York, 1958 June 17; 3 color slides (Box 226)
        Slide numbers 2023, 2024, 2025. Image set number CXXXc.
      - Bethune, Mary McLeod, 1949 April 6; 7 color slides (Box 224)
        Slide numbers 915, 916, 917, 918, 919, 920, 921. Image set number XXVb.
      - Blackwell, Charles, 1955 July 5; 11 color slides (Box 225)
        Slide numbers 1734, 1737, 1738, 1739, 1740, 1741, 1743, 1745, 1746, 1747, 1748. Image set number LXXXVIIc. Image 1734 depicts Blackwell wearing a wrapper (also known as a lappa) of the Fante (also known as Mfantsefo). Image 1737-1741 depict him wearing a sabador from Sengal. Image 1743-1748 depict him wearing traditional Tutsi dress (referred to as Watusi)
      - Blancos, Ramón, in Havana, Cuba, 1951 March 11; 1 color slide (Box 224)
        Slide number 955. Image set number LXVIIIb.
      - Boatwright, McHenry, 1961 December 5; 10 color slides (Box 226)
        Slide numbers 2152, 2153, 2154, 2155, 2156, 2157, 2158, 2159, 2160, 2161. Image set number CLXXIXc.
      - Bonds, Margaret, 1956 October 10; 3 color slides (Box 224)
        Slide numbers 1290, 1291, 1292. Image set number CVc.
      - Bontemps, Arna, and Paul Bontemps at Fisk University, Nashville, Tennessee, 1947 April 26; 1 color slide (Box 224)
        Slide number 887. Image set number CCLVIa.
      - Bontemps, Arna, with Horace R. (Horace Roscoe) Cayton and Langston Hughes at Fisk University, Nashville, Tennessee, 1947 April 26; 1 color slide (Box 224)
        Slide number 889. Image set number CCLVIa.
      - Bontemps, Arna, with Horace R. (Horace Roscoe) Cayton at Fisk University, Nashville, Tennessee, 1947 April 26; 1 color slide (Box 224)
        Slide number 891. Image set number CCLVIa.
      - Bontemps, Arna, with Langston Hughes and Harold Jackman, 1942 June 11; 3 color slides (Box 223)
        Slide numbers 432, 433, 434. Image set number IVa.
      - Bontemps, Paul, at Fisk University, Nashville, Tennessee, 1947 April 26; 2 color slides (Box 224)
        Slide numbers 885, 886. Image set number CCLVIa.
      - Bradshaw, Tiny, 1942 March 19; 5 color slides (Box 223)
        Slide numbers 326, 327, 328, 329, 330. Image set number CCCXCIII.
      - Braithwaite, E. R. (Edward Ricardo), 1962 April 26; 7 color slides (Box 226)
        Slide numbers 2182, 2183, 2184, 2185, 2186, 2187, 2188. Image set number CLXXXIVc.
      - Braithwaite, William Stanley, 1947 March 27; 5 color slides (Box 224)
        Slide numbers 873, 874, 875, 876, 877. Image set number CCLIV.
      - Brice, Carol, 1947 April 10; 11 color slides (Box 223)
        Slide numbers 684, 685, 686, 687, 688, 689, 690, 691, 692, 693, 694. Image set number CCLVa.
      - Brice, Jonathan, 1953 March 3; 9 color slides (Box 224)
        Slide numbers 1402, 1403, 1404, 1405, 1406, 1407, 1408, 1409, 1410. Image set number XIXc.
      - Bricktop, 1939; 2 color slides (Box 223)
        Slide numbers 732, 733. Image set number LVII.
      - Brooks, Maurice, at Fisk University, Nashville, Tennessee, 1947 April 26; 2 color slides (Box 224)
        Slide numbers 896, 897. Image set number CCLVIa.
      - Brown, Anne, 1948 February 18; 7 color slides (Box 223)
        Slide numbers 701, 702, 703, 704, 705, 706, 707. Image set number CCLXXVa.
      - Brown, Debria, as Carmen in Carmen, opera by Georges Bizet and libretto by Henri Meilhac and Ludovic Halévy, 1958 December 15; 19 color slides (Box 224)
        Slide numbers 1540, 1541, 1542, 1543, 1544, 1545, 1546, 1547, 1548, 1549, 1550, 1551, 1552, 1553, 1554, 1555, 1556, 1557, 1558. Image set number CXXXVIIIc. Inscriptions on mounts misidentify the creation date as December 16, 1959.
      - Browne, Roscoe Lee, 1964 January 14; 10 color slides (Box 226)
        Slide numbers 2268, 2269, 2270, 2271, 2272, 2273, 2274, 2275, 2276, 2277. No image set number.
      - Bryant, Joyce, 1953 May 28; 19 color slides (Box 224)
        Slide numbers 1122, 1123, 1124, 1125, 1126, 1127, 1128, 1129, 1130, 1131, 1132, 1133, 1134, 1135, 1136, 1137, 1138, 1139, 1140. Image set number XXVIIIc. Bryant wears gowns designed by Zelda Wynn Valdes.
      - Bunche, Ralph J. (Ralph Johnson), 1951 May 16; 6 color slides (Box 224)
        Slide numbers 1213, 1214, 1215, 1216, 1217, 1218. Image set number LXXIVb.
      - Burleigh, H. T. (Harry Thacker), 1941; 3 color slides (Box 223)
        Slide numbers 304, 305, 306, 308, 309. Image set number CCLV.
      - Burley, Dan, 1947 November 13; 2 color slides (Box 224)
        Slide numbers 1049, 1050. Image set number CCLXVIIa.
      - Burton, Miriam, 1958 May 10; 7 color slides (Box 224)
        Slide numbers 1451, 1452, 1453, 1454, 1455, 1456, 1457. Image set number CXXVIIIc.
      - Burton, Miriam, and Diedre Greenway, 1958 May 10; 1 color slide (Box 224)
        Slide number 1458. Image set number CXXVIIIc.
      - Cardozo, Edna, 1951 October 18; 1 color slide (Box 224)
        Slide number 1019. Image set number LXXXIIIb. Wife of Frank Cardozo, owner of Hotel Beau-Site (later Hôtel Montana) in Port-au-Prince, Haiti.
      - Carlis, John, Jr., 1958 November 11; 3 color slides (Box 226)
        Slide numbers 2044, 2045, 2046. Image set number CXXXVIIc.
      - Carpenter, Thelma, 1949 March 9; 4 color slides (Box 223)
        Slide numbers 844, 845, 846, 847. Image set number XXIVb. Carpenter wears a Seminole costume, and a Hopi/Navajo silver squash blossom necklace.
      - Carroll, Diahann, 1955 March 14; 20 color slides (Box 224)
        Slide numbers 1244, 1245, 1246, 1247, 1248, 1249, 1250, 1251, 1252, 1253, 1254, 1255, 1256, 1257, 1258, 1259, 1260, 1261, 1262, 1263. Image set number LXVIIc. Images numbered 1251-1263 depict Carroll in a "gown by Edwin," probably Edwin Hardy Amies.
      - Carter, John Wallace, 1958 November 18; 6 color slides (Box 226)
        Slide numbers 2047, 2048, 2049, 2050, 2051, 2052. Image set number CXXXVIIc.
      - Carter, Shirley Venett, 1961 August 8; 10 color slides (Box 225)
        Slide numbers 1723, 1724, 1725, 1726, 1727, 1728, 1729, 1730, 1731, 1732. Image set number CLXXVIc.
      - Cayton, Horace R. (Horace Roscoe), 1948; 3 color slides (Box 224)
        Slide numbers 892, 893, 894. Image set number XIIIb.
      - Cayton, Horace R. (Horace Roscoe), and Langston Hughes at Fisk University, Nashville, Tennessee, 1947 April 26; 1 color slide (Box 224)
        Slide number 890. Image set number CCLVIa.
      - Cayton, Horace R. (Horace Roscoe), and Ruby Wright Cayton, 1948; 1 color slide (Box 224)
        Slide number 895. Image set number XIIIb.
      - Cayton, Horace R. (Horace Roscoe), at Fisk University, Nashville, Tennessee, 1947 April 26; 1 color slide (Box 224)
        Slide number 888. Image set number CCLVIa.
      - Clay, Fannie S., and Bill Robinson, 1941 April 18; 2 color slides (Box 223)
        Slide numbers 216, 217. Image set number CCCXXV.
      - Clay, Omar, 1962 October 30; 8 color slides (Box 226)
        Slide numbers 2221, 2222, 2223, 2224, 2225, 2226, 2227, 2228. Image set number CLXXXIXc.
      - Cleveland, Lady Bird, 1954 September 21; 13 color slides (Box 223)
        Slide numbers 1177, 1178, 1179, 1180, 1181, 1182, 1183, 1184, 1186, 1187, 1188, 1189, 1190, 1191. Image set number LVIIc. Several portraits include Cleveland with her paintings "Harlem Scene," "Model" (also known as "Portrait of a Negro NY") and "Self-Portrait."
      - Cleveland, Lady Bird, and Patricia Cleveland, 1959 July 28; 1 color slide (Box 224)
        Slide number 1191-9, 1191-10. Image set number CLc.
      - Coleman, Leo, as Toby in The Medium, opera by Gian Carlo Menotti, 1946 May 18; 16 color slides (Box 223)
        Slide numbers 734, 735, 736, 737, 738, 739, 740, 741, 742, 743, 744, 745, 746, 747, 748, 749. Image set number CCXXVa.
      - Collins, Durward, 1962 September 5; 8 color slides (Box 226)
        Slide numbers 2213, 2214, 2215, 2216, 2217, 2218, 2219, 2220. Image set number CLXXXVIIc.
      - Collins, Janet, in La Creole, dance choreographed by Janet Collins, 1949 April 23; 8 color slides (Box 224)
        Slide numbers 944, 945, 946, 947, 949, 950, 952, 954. Image set number XXVIb.
      - Collins, Janet, in Rondo, a ballet from Eine Kleine Nachtmusik, composed by Wolfgang Amadeus Mozart, choreographed by Janet Collins, 1949 April 23; 3 color slides (Box 224)
        Slide numbers 938, 939, 941. Image set number XXVIb.
      - Collins, Janet, in Spirituals, dance choreographed by Janet Collins, 1949 April 23; 2 color slides (Box 224)
        Slide numbers 932, 933. Image set number XXVb.
      - Collins, Zebedee, 1953 February 10; 3 color slides (Box 224)
        Slide numbers 1327/1328, 1331, 1332. Image set number XVIIc.
      - Collins, Zebedee, and Lorenzo Newby, 1953 February 10; 17 color slides (Box 224)
        Slide numbers 1321, 1322, 1323, 1324, 1333, 1334, 1335, 1336, 1337, 1338, 1339/1340, 1341, 1342, 1343, 1344, 1345, 1346/1347. Image set number XVIIc. Image numbers 1133-1336 depict Collins and Newby performing "Alunda"; image number 1337-1339/1340 depict Collins and Newby performing "Batu."
      - Cook, Muriel, and Dorothy Williams in Black Ritual (Obeah), ballet choreographed by Agnes de Mille, music by Darius Milhaud, 1940 April 8; 1 color slide (Box 223)
        Slide number 454. Image set number LXXXVII.
      - Cook, Muriel, in Black Ritual (Obeah), ballet choreographed by Agnes de Mille, music by Darius Milhaud, 1940 April 8; 1 color slide (Box 223)
        Slide number 466. Image set number LXXXVII.
      - Cook, Muriel, with Lawaune Kennard and Dorothy Williams in Black Ritual (Obeah), ballet choreographed by Agnes de Mille, music by Darius Milhaud, 1940 April 8; 1 color slide (Box 223)
        Slide number 463. Image set number LXXXVII.
      - Corbin, Clayton, 1954 October 23; 7 color slides (Box 224)
        Slide numbers 1559, 1560, 1561, 1562, 1563, 1564, 1565. Image set number LIXc.
      - Cortor, Eldzier, 1959 June 7; 2 color slides (Box 226)
        Slide numbers 2072, 2073. Image set number CXLVIIc. Inscriptions on mounts misidentifies the date as June 9, 1959.
      - Cortor, Eldzier, with his artwork, 1959 June 7; 3 color slides (Box 226)
        Slide numbers 2074, 2075, 2076. Image set number CXLVIIc. Artwork is an ink drawing, Composition - Heads. Inscription on mount misidentifies the date as June 9, 1959.
      - Creswell, Pearl, and Carl Van Vechten at the Carl Van Vechten Gallery, Fisk University, Nashville, Tennessee, 1957 May 14; 1 color slide (Box 224)
        Slide number 882D. No image set number.
      - Cullen, Countee, 1941 June 15; 4 color slides (Box 223)
        Slide numbers 240, 241, 242,243. Image set number CCCLII.
      - Cullen, Countee, at Central Park, New York City, 1941 September 20; 1 color slide (Box 223)
        Slide number 244. Image set number CCCLXXIV.
      - Curtis, Robert, 1955 April 19; 11 color slides (Box 225)
        Slide numbers 1676, 1677, 1678, 1679, 1682, 1683, 1684, 1686, 1688, 1689, 1690. Image set number LXXIIIc.
      - Daniels, Jimmie, 1940; 7 color slides (Box 223)
        Slide numbers 157, 158, 159, 160, 161, 162, 163. Image set number XCIX.
      - Daniels, Jimmie, 1963 January 29; 3 color slides (Box 226)
        Slide numbers 163-1, 163-2, 163-3. Image set number CXCIIc.
      - Davis, Ossie, 1951 April 12; 2 color slides (Box 224)
        Slide numbers 1109, 1110. Image set number LXXb.
      - Davis, Ossie, and Ruby Dee, 1961 November 15; 1 color slide (Box 225)
        Slide number 1782. Image set number CLXXXVIIIc.
      - Davis, Ossie, as Gabriel in The Green Pastures, play by Marc Connelly adapted from Ol' Man Adam an' His Chillun by Roark Bradford, 1951 April 12; 4 color slides (Box 224)
        Slide numbers 1111, 1112, 1118, 1119. Image set number LXXb.
      - Davis, Ossie, as Gabriel, and William Marshall as God in The Green Pastures, play by Marc Connelly adapted from Ol' Man Adam an' His Chillun by Roark Bradford, 1951 April 12; 3 color slides (Box 224)
        Slide numbers 1113, 1114, 1117. Image set number LXXb.
      - Davy, Gloria, 1958 February 22; 3 color slides (Box 224)
        Slide numbers 1426, 1427, 1428. Image set number CXXIIIc.
      - Davy, Gloria, in Aida, an opera by Giuseppe Verdi with libretto by Antonio Ghislanzoni, 1958 February 22; 13 color slides (Box 224)
        Slide numbers 1411, 1412, 1413, 1414, 1415, 1416, 1417, 1418, 1419/1420, 1421, 1423, 1424, 1425. Image set numbers. CXXIIc and CXXIIIc.
      - De Lavallade, Carmen, 1955 March 3; 12 color slides (Box 224)
        Slide numbers 1220, 1222, 1224, 1226, 1229, 1231, 1232, 1234, 1235, 1236, 1237, 1239. Image set number LXVIc.
      - De Lavallade, Carmen, and Leo Holder, 1958 December 26; 3 color slides (Box 224)
        Slide numbers 1534, 1535, 1536. Image set number CXXXIXc.
      - De Paur, Leonard, 1958 November 11; 3 color slides (Box 224)
        Slide numbers 1493, 1494, 1495. Image set number CXXXVIIc.
      - De Paur, Leonard, and Norma Childs De Paur, 1958 November 11; 2 color slides (Box 224)
        Slide numbers 1496, 1497. Image set number CXXXVIIc.
      - Dee, Ruby, 1961 November 15; 6 color slides (Box 225)
        Slide numbers 1776, 1777, 1778, 1779, 1780, 1781. Image set number CLXXVIIIc.
      - Dee, Ruby, 1962 September 25; 15 color slides (Box 225)
        Slide numbers 1782-1, 1782-2, 1782-3, 1782-4, 1782-5, 1782-6, 1782-7, 1782-8, 1782-9, 1782-10, 1782-11, 1782-12, 1782-13, 1782-14, 1782-15. Image set number CLXXVIIIc.
      - Delaney, Beauford, 1953 March 18; 5 color slides (Box 224)
        Slide numbers 1429, 1430, 1431, 1432, 1433. Image set number XXIc.
      - Demby, William, 1956 March 13; 2 color slides (Box 225)
        Slide numbers 1901, 1902. Image set number XCIXc.
      - Dickerson, Inez, 1951 July 4; 1 color slide (Box 224)
        Slide number 995. Image set number LXXVIIb.
      - Dilworth, Hubert, 1963 August 28; 8 color slides (Box 226)
        Slide numbers 2246, 2247, 2248, 2249, 2250, 2251, 2252, 2253. No image set number. Inscription misidentifies the date as August 27, 1963.
      - Dixon, Dean, 1941 September 17; 10 color slides (Box 223)
        Slide numbers 95, 96, 97, 98, 99, 100, 101, 102, 103, 104. Image set number CCCLXXIII.
      - Dobbs, Mattiwilda, 1955 January 25; 9 color slides (Box 224)
        Slide numbers 1204, 1205, 1206, 1207, 1208, 1209, 1210, 1211, 1212. Image set number LXIVc.
      - Dodson, Owen, 1942 June 18; 12 color slides (Box 224)